SUMMARY



■ syedshoib25@gmail.com **८** 91-982 336 6765

Software Engineer with 1.5+ years of professional experience and 3+ years of freelancing experience. Expertise in front-end and back-end development, specializing in JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, MongoDB, and Docker. Known for strong problem-solving abilities, adaptability, and a quick learning curve.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- **Programming Language:** Java, C, C++, Python
- Frontend: JavaScript, React.js, Redux, Next.js 13, TypeScript, Tailwind-CSS, Material-UI
- Backend: Node.js, Express.js, and TypeScript
- Databases: MongoDB, MySql,
- **DevOps and Automation:** Kubernetes , Docker, Jenkins
- Others: Git, Agile, Gitlab,

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Feb 2023 - Ongoing

Techweaver Systems (Startup) (React.js, Node.js, Mongodb)

Hyderabad, India

- Integrated **OAuth** authentication providers with **Firebase Authentication** to enable users to sign in using their existing accounts from Google, Facebook, **Led 5 successful projects** update release cycles.
- Developed and implemented a new front-end architecture using React.js resulting in a **25% increase** in page load speed and a **15% increase** in user engagement.
- Implemented and maintained front-end web applications, resulting in a 20% reduction in page load speeds and
 conversion rates by utilizing modern web technologies such as React.js and best practices for user experience and
 accessibility.
- Developed 6 interactive front-end applications using the React.js library and Next.js, enhancing consumer experience by 35%.

Freelance Java Developer

Oct 2021 - Jan 2023

Upwork (Core Java, Java EE,)

Remote

- Contributed to the development and maintenance of **6+** web applications using **Java/J2EE** technologies, resulting in a **30**% increase in client satisfaction."
- Contributed to the development and maintenance of Java applications for diverse clients, including e-commerce platforms, content management systems, and financial applications.

Freelance Front-End Developer

Dec 2019 - Aug 2021

Fiverrr (JavaScript, React.js, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap)

Remote

- Developed and deployed over 15 front-end websites, showcasing a keen eye for design and functionality
- Collaborated closely with clients to translate their vision into user-friendly interfaces, resulting in high satisfaction rates
- Implemented feedback from clients to continuously improve designs and meet project goals
- Ensured cross-browser compatibility and optimized performance for all projects

PROJECTS (7)

Cache-Enabled-Multi-Threaded-Proxy 🗘

- Designed and implemented a **high-performance**, **cache-enabled multi-threaded proxy server**in C, optimizing server performance with **socket programming**, and **efficient caching** mechanisms.
- Led design of **high-performance** C proxy server, optimizing concurrency with **socket programming**, **caching**, and **multithreading**.
- Implemented advanced caching for faster response times and scalability, boosting server performance.

Disney+ Clone (7)

- Created a fully functional replica of the Disney+ streaming platform using React.js for the front end
- Utilized the Movie Database API to fetch and display movie and TV show data, implementing dynamic API routes for efficient data retrieval.

Full Stack Airbnb Clone (7)

- Utilized MongoDB to manage and store user data, property listings, and booking information efficiently.
- Designed and implemented a robust backend using **Node.js** and **Express.js** to handle server-side logic, user **authentication**, and data management.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science | CGPA: 8.72

Aug. 2019 — Nov 2022

S.R.T.M.U

Nanded, India

Coursework: Java, Data Structure And Algorithm, Software Testing, Software Engineering, Object-Oriented Programming, Operating System, Relational Database Management System, SQL, Visual Basic, C++.

Area of Interest: Big Data, Web3, Distributed Systems, Cloud Computing